Guide to the Reference Center for Marxist Studies Pamphlet Collection PE.043
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Debs, Eugene (12 pamphlets and an article) (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Cannon, James P. Eugene V. Debs. Pioneer Publishers, New York, NY., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Debs, Theodore. Sidelights Incidents in the Life of Eugene V. Debs. Eugene V. Debs Foundation., 1973 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley. Debs and Dennis Fighters for Peace. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - London, Jack. The Dream of Debs. Charles H. Kerr and Company. (2 copies), undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Hollingsworth, J. H. Eugene V. Debs What His Neighbors Say of Him., undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Sharp, Clarence. The Dream of Debs and the Double Dealing of President Woodrow Wilson. West End Press, Minneapolis, MN. (2 copies), 1981 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - The Debs Case a Complete History. The National Socialist Office, Chicago, IL., undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Trachtenberg, Alexander. The Heritage of Gene Debs. International Pamphlets, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1930 (Box 28, Folder 6)
- De Leon, Daniel (5 pamphlets) (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - De Leon, Daniel. Two Pages from Roman History. New York Labor News Company, New York, NY., 1943 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Johnson, Oakley C. and Carl Reeve. Writings by and about Daniel De Leon: A Bibliography. The American Institute for Marxist Studies, New York, NY., 1966 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Petersen, Arnold. Daniel De Leon Internationalist. New York Labor News Company, New York, NY., 1944 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Petersen, Arnold. Daniel De Leon Social Architect. New York Labor News Company, New York, NY., 1941 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Petersen, Arnold. De Leon the Uncompromising. New York Labor News Company, New York, NY., 1939 (Box 28, Folder 7)
- Democracy (12 pamphlets) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Collins, Mary. Democracy in Danger. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Democracy in Trade Unions. American Civil Liberties Union, New York, NY., 1944 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Every Cook Can Govern: A Study of Democracy in Ancient Greece. Correspondence Publishing Co., Detroit, MI., 1956 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Gollan, John. Democracy and Class Struggle. Lawrence and Wishart, London., undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Krumbein, Charles and Israel Amter. Dollars for Democracy. (3 copies), undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - On People's Democracy in Eastern Europe and China: A Selection of Articles and Speeches. The Communist Party., 1951 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - The American Legion and the Communists Discuss Democracy. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1938 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - The Political Animal. Fund for the Republic., 1962 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Deportation (12 pamphlets as well as brochures) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - American Deportation and Exclusion Laws. Workers Defense Union, New York, NY., undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - American Homes in Danger! Exile for Mothers Threatens Homes!. National Women's Appeal for the Rights of Foreign Born Americans. New York, NY., undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Deportation its Meaning and Menace Last Message to the People of America by Alexander Berkman and Emma Goldman. New York, NY., 1919 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - End Exile. American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born. New York, NY., undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Free Ferrero and Sallitto. Ferrero-Sallitto Defense Conference of New York, New York, NY., undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Green, Abner. The Deportation Drive vs the Bill of Rights the McCarran Act and the Foreign Born. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1951 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Green, Abner. The Deportation Terror a Weapon to Gag America. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Since the Buford Sailed: A Summary of the Developments in the Deportation Situation. American Civil Liberties Union, New York, NY., undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - We Need a Statute of Limitation!. American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, New York, NY. (3 copies) (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Depression Years (22 pamphlets) (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Benjamin, Herbert. A Handbook for Project Workers. New York, NY. (3 copies), 1936 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Benjamin, Herbert. How to Organize and Conduct United Action for the Right to Live. National Committee Unemployed Councils, New York, NY., 1933 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Buddy, Can You Spare the Time?. Communist Party of Illinois, Chicago, IL., undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Burton, Bernard. A New Depression?. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1949 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Chambers, Whittaker. Can You Hear Their Voices a Short Story. International Pamphlets, New York, NY., 1932 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Collins, Mary. The Fight for Recovery Stop the Sit-Down Strike of Big Business. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1938 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Cowl, Margaret. The High Cost of Living: How to Bring it Down. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1937 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Foster, William Z. Fight Against Hunger Statement Drafted by C.P.U.S.A. and Presented to Fish Committee. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1930 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Laidler, Harry W. America in the Depression. League for Industrial Democracy, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Morton, Joseph. Depression Hard Facts vs. Soft Soap. The Pacific Publishing Foundation, San Francisco, CA. (5 copies), undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Terror Against the People the Story of the WPA Witch Hunt. Joint Committee to Defend W.P.A. Workers, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Van Veen, Sadie. Our Children Cry for Bread. National Committee Unemployed Councils, New York, NY., 1933 (Box 29, Folder 3)
- Developing Countries (1 pamphlet) (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Simai, Mihaly. Studies on Developing Countries: Planning and Plan Implementation in the Developing Countries. Institute for World Economics of the Hungarian Academy of Sciences, Budapest., 1975 (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Dialectical Materialism (8 pamphlets) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Cornforth, Maurice. Dialectical Materialism and Science. Lawrence and Wishart, London. (2 copies), 1949 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Cornforth, Maurice. Materialism and the Dialectical Method. International Publishers, New York, NY., 1972 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Haldane, J. B. S. Dialectical Materialism and Modern Science. Labour Monthly, London. (2 copies), undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Rosental, M. Dialectics of the Present Epoch. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Rudas, L. Dialectical Materialism and Communism. Labour Monthly Pamphlets, London. (2 copies), circa 1933 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Teryaev, G. A.I. Herzen: Great Russian Thinker and Revolutionary Democrat. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1954 (Box 29, Folder 5)
- Dictatorship of the Proletariat (1 pamphlet) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Once More about the Historical Experience of the Dictatorship of the Proletariat. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1957 (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Dies Committee I (contains an edition of The Nation (1942) about Martin Dies) (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - The Nation: Martin Dies and His Committee on "un-Americanism." The Nation, New York, NY., 1942 (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Dies Committee II (10 pamphlets) (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Lapin, Adam. The Un-American Dies Committee. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (4 copies), 1939 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - The Activities of the Dies Committee an Analysis. American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom. New York, NY., 1940 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - The Dies Committee Inquisition "a Sordid Procedure". American League for Peace and Democracy, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1939 (Box 29, Folder 8)
- Dimitroff, George I (14 pamphlets) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - An Outstanding Revolutionary and Leninist: In Commemoration of the 90th Anniversary of the Birth of Georgi Dimitrov. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1972 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Data for a Report on the Life and Work of Georgi Dimitrov. Sofia Press, Sofia, Bulgaria., 1972 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. The Struggle Against the Imperialist War. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1940 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. The War and the Working Class. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Dimitroff, G. The United Front Against Fascism and War. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Dimitrov versus Goering. German Reich Supreme Court., 1933 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Jerome, V.J. The Path Dimitroff Charted. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1943 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - George Dimitroff. International Publishers, New York, NY., 1943 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - George Dimitrov: Brief Biographical Notes. Sofia Press., undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Georgi Dimitrov., undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Georgi Dimitrov: 90th Birth Anniversary. Peace and Socialism Publishers, Prague. (2 copies), 1972 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Radenkova, Petra. Georgi Dimitrov: A Short Biography. Sofia Press., 1978 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Zhivkov, Todor. May the Name and Lifework of Georgi Dimitrov Live Through the Centuries. Sofia Press., 1972 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Dimitroff, George II (24 pamphlets) (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitroff Accuses. Daily Worker, New York, NY., 1934 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitroff, G. The United Struggle For Peace. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1936 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. After Munich. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1939 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. Fascism Is War. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1937 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. To Defend Assassins Is to Help Fascism. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1937 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. The Struggle Against the Imperialist War. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1940 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. The War and the Working Class. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (5 copies), 1939 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitroff. Working Class Unity-Bulwark Against Fascism. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitrov Accuses the Nazis. The Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1941 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitrov, G. The Soviet Union and the Working Class of the Capitalist Countries. Co-Operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1937 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitrov, G. Unity and Peace. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dimitrov, Georgi. The Government Declaration. Ministry of Information and Arts, Sofia, Bulgaria., 1947 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - George Dimitroff. International Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Jerome, V.J. The Path Dimitroff Chartered. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1943 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Working Class Unity - Bulward Against Fascism. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Dimitroff, George III (13 pamphlets) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - An Outstanding Revolutionary and Leninist: In Commemoration of the 90th Anniversary of the Birth of Georgi Dimitrov. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1972 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Bulgarian Cultural News. Committee for Science, Art and Culture, Sofia., 1952 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. Working Class Unity-Bulwark Against Fascism. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Dimitrov, Georgi. Yet It Moves! Sofia Press. (2 copies), 1978 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Dimitrov versus Goering. German Reich Supreme Court., 1933 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - George Dimitroff. International Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Georgi Dimitrov and the Contemporary World. Sofia Press., undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Georgi Dimitrov: Dedicated Fighter for Peace. World Peace Council, Helsinki., 1972 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Georgi Dimitrov: Short Biographical Notes. Ministry of Information and Art, Bulgaria., 1946 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Jermone, V.J. The Path Dimitroff Charted. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1943 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - The Georgi Dimitrov: Museum House., undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Zhivkov, Todor. May the Name and Lifework of Georgi Dimitrov Live Through the Centuries. Sofia Press., 1972 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Dimitroff, George IV (12 pamphlets) (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitroff Accuses. Daily Worker, New York, NY., 1934 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitroff, G. The Legal System of German Fascism: Reply to Herr Ribbentrop. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1936 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitroff, G. The United Front Against Fascism and War. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitroff, G. The United Struggle for Peace. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1936 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitrov, G. The Soviet Union and the Working Class of the Capitalist Countries. Co-Operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1937 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. After Munich. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1938 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. The Guarantee of Victory. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1938 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. The War and the Working Class of the Capitalist Countries., undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dimitroff, Georgi. The War and the Working Class. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1939 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - The Truth About the Behavior of the Leader of the Bulgarian Opposition and the Twenty Three Opposition M. P.'S. Ministry of Information and Arts, Press Department, Sofia, Bulgaria., 1947 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Disarmament I (16 pamphlets) (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Buck, Tim. Disarmament Means Peace. Progress Books, Toronto, Ontario., 1959 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Blackett, P.M.S. The Military Background to Disarmament...Marzani & Munsell, Inc., New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Disarmament and the American Economy. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1960 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Economic Aspects of Disarmament. International Institute for Peace, Vienna, Austria., 1963 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Freedom From War: The United States Program for General and Complete Disarmament in a Peaceful World. Department of State, Washington, D.C., 1961 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Gorbachev, Mikhail. A Real Step Towards Real Disarmament. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1986 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Khrushchov, N.S. General and Complete Disarmament is a Guarantee of Peace and Security For All Nations. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Lumer, Hyman. Disarmament and the American Economy. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1960 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Report of Arden House Conference on Disarmament. Committee for World Development and World Disarmament, New York, NY., 1958 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Simon, Mildred. Peace or Perish. The Emma Lazarus Federation of Jewish Women's Clubs, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1962 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - The Story of Disarmament, 1945-1962. Disarmament Committee of the Washington, D.C. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Towrad Security Through Disarmament. American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia, PA., 1952 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Urban, L. and J. Pokstefl. General Disarmament: Prerequisites and Prospects. Peace and Socialism Publishers, Prague., 1965 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Disarmament II (17 pamphlets) (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - A Southerner Looks At Negro Discrimination. International Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1946 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Negro Propaganda in School Textbooks. The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, New York, NY., 1939 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Dialogue on Security and Disarmament in Europe. International Liasion Forum of Peace Forces, Stockholm., 1984 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - European Youth and Student Conference on Disarmament. Budapest., 1978 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Everybody's business: A summary of New York State Anti-Discrimination Laws and how to use them. National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, New York, NY., 1946 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - For the World Without Arms and Wars. World Federation of Trade Unions, Prague., 1981 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Khrushchov, N.S. General and Complete Disarmament is a Guarantee of Peace and Security for All Nations. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Khrushchev, N.S. Total Disarmament In Four Years. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1959 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Lunacharsky, A. The Soviets Fight For Disarmament. International Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Mass Media and Disarmament. Internatinoal Organization of Journalists, Prague., undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Morray, J.P. The Real Issues At Geneva: The Strategy for Disarmament. New World Review, New York, NY., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Peace - Disarmament - Co-Operation - the Objects of Our Struggle. Women's International Democratic Federation, Berlin., 1979 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Problems of Disarmament. Monthly Review Press, New York, NY., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Problems of Disarmament: Soviet Viewpoint. Soviet Peace Committee, Helsinki, Finland., 1978 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Swords into Plowshares: Soviet Initiatives for Peace, Security & Disarmament. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, New York, NY., 1982 (Box 31, Folder 2)
- Disarmament III (15 pamphlets and a brochure) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Bernal, J.D. Disarmament. British Peace Committee, London., undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Call to the June 12th Rally. June 12 Rally Committee, New York, NY., undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Chater, Tony. The Case for Peace and Disarmament. Communist Party of Great Britain., undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Disarmament and the American Economy. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1960 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Fischer, Oskar. Viewpoint of the GDR expressed at UN Special Session: Removing the threat of a nuclear war is the most urgent task., 1982 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Gromyko, Andrei. On Practical Ways to End the Arms Race: Proposals of the Soviet Union. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1978 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Jack, Homer A. Toward Nuclear Disarmament. American Humanist Association, Yellow Spring, Ohio., 1961 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Lumer, Hyman. Disarmament and the American Economy. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1960 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Messages: Premier Nikita S. Khrushchev To Heads of Governments of the Countries of the World, President Lyndon B. Johnson Reply to the Message of Premier Khrushchev, President Lyndon B. Johnson to the Disarmament Conference in Geneva. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, New York, NY., 1964 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Morray, J.P. The Real Issues At Geneva: The Strategy for Disarmament. New World Review, New York, NY., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - New proposals on disarmament, security and confidence-building. Political Consultative Committee, Marsaw., 1988 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Nuclear Testing and Disarmament. United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, Washington, D.C., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Problems of Struggle Against the Arms Race., undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - The 2nd Vienna Dialogue: International Conference for Disarmament and Detente. International Liaison Forum of Peace Forces, Helsinki, Finland., 1983 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - The Treaty between the Soviet Union and the United States on the Elimination of their Intermediate and Shorter-range Missiles: A new stage in the struggle for peace and disarmament. Verlag Zeit im Bild, Dresden., 1987 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Zdanowicz, Jerzv and Jan Kulig. Disarmament and Development. Information Centre of the World Peace Council, Helsinki, Finland (2 copies)., undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Disarmament IV (13 pamphlets) (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Arkadyev, N. General and Complete Disarmament - The Road to Peace. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Blackett, P.M.S. The Military Background to Disarmament... Marzani & Munsell Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Gromyko, Andrei. On Practical Ways to End the Arms Race: Proposals of the Soviet Union. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1978 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Guerre, Brian Alan. Who's Responsible? A Comparison of the U.S. and Soviet Records in the Arms Race and in the Disarmament Process. US Peace Council, New York, NY., 1984 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Khrushchov, N.S. General and Complete Disarmament is a Guarantee of Peace and Security for All Nations. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Lippay, Z. Behind the Scenes of the Disarmament Conference. Cooperative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the USSR, Moscow., 1932 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Lumer, Hyman. Disarmament and the American Economy. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1960 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Maximova, M. Global Problems and Peace Among Nations. International Peace and Disarmament, Moscow., 1982 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Problems of Disarmament. Monthly Review Press, New York, NY., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Questions on Disarmament and Your Job. Friends Committee on National Legislation, Washington, D.C., undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Sibley, Mulford. Unilateral Initiatives and Disarmament. American Friends Service Committee., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - The Story of Disarmament, 1945-1963. Disarmament Committee of the Washington, D.C., 1962 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Urban, L. and J. Pokstefl. General Disarmament: Prerequisites and Prospects. Peace and Socialism Publishers, Prague., 1965 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Disarmament: Economic Aspects (5 pamphlets) (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Disarmament and the American Economy. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1960 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Economic and Social Consequences of Disarmament: Report of the Secretary-General Transmitting the Study of His Consultative Group. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, New York, NY., 1962 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Economic Aspects of Disarmament. International Institute for Peace, Vienna, Austria., 1963 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Economic Impacts of Disarmament. United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, Washington, D.C., 1962 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Report of Gould House Conference on Economics of Disarmament. Committee for World Development and World Disarmament, New York, NY., 1961 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Discrimination (13 pamphlets) (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - An 80 Year Wait. Coordinating Committee for the Enforcement of the D.C. Anti-Discrimination Laws., 1953 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Negro Propaganda in School Textbooks. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, New York, NY., 1939 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Black Justice. American Civil Liberties Union, New York, NY., 1931 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Cable, George W. A Southerner Looks at Negro Discrimination. International Publishers, New York. NY., 1946 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Cracking the Color Line. Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), New York, NY., undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Discrimination Costs You Money. National Labor Service, New York, NY., undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Everybody's Business: A Summary of New York State Anti-Discrimination Laws and How to Use Them. National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, New York, NY., 1946 (Box 32, Folder 2)